Guide to the Henry R. Luce Papers 1894-2004 (bulk, 1932-1967) MS 3014
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Family Correspondence and School Records, 1898-1973 (bulk, 1898-1948); 205876; 8.2 Linear feet
  - Hotchkiss, 1915 (folder 1 of 2), 215218 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    Includes the words for a school song by HRL "The White and Blue."
  - Hotchkiss, 1915 (folder 2 of 2), 215226 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    Includes letters sent by HRL from Mill Valley, California, the West Coast and Chicago during his summer vacation.
  - Hotchkiss, 1916, 215229 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    Includes the first typewritten letter sent by HRL to his parents, a letter from Knox Hat Company to HRL regarding advertisement in The Hotchkiss Literary Monthly, and a letter from H. G. Buehler, headmaster of Hotchkiss, to Henry W. Luce complaining about HRL.
  - Summer of 1916 at Springfield, before Yale, 215230 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    Includes a note to HRL from his father regarding Dr. Buehler, a letter regarding journalistic opportunities in China, and letters from Linair and Williams Club in NY. Part of a letter is missing.
  - Yale, 1916-1917 (folder 1 of 2), 215231 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    Includes two typed letters to HRL from his father, HRL letters sent from NY and Chicago, and HRL's report card.
  - Yale, 1916-1917 (folder 2 of 2), 215232 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    Includes a typed letter to HRL from his father giving his son advice on classes, fraternities and other matters pertaining to Yale.
  - Summer of 1917 (folder 1 of 2), 215235 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    Letters from Linair where HRL spent the summer working on a farm.
  - Summer of 1917 (folder 2 of 2), 215236 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Yale, 1917-1918 (folder 1 of 2), 215237 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    Includes an Alpha Delta Phi fraternity card addressed to HRL and the poem "Le Credo Patriotique" by Henry Lavedan.
  - Yale, 1917-1918 (folder 2 of 2), 215238 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    6 May 1918 letter includes HRL's opinions of marriage.
  - Yale Daily News (Special File), 1918, 1917-1918; 215243 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    Includes clipping announcing HRL's election to the editorial board of the News, a note on a telegram form from HRL's father? regarding HRL having been elected, and other correspondence regarding HRL's chairmanship of the News.
  - Wartime Letters from the Summer of 1918 to January 1919 and Return to Yale, 215246 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    Includes HRL's military pass, transparencies of some of the letters, a letter to Aunt Flo, a letter to Mrs. McCormick, a letter to HRL from Dean of Yale, Frederick S. Jones, and a sketch of Camp Taylor? Part of a letter is missing.
  - Yale, 1919-1920 (folder 1 of 2), 215247 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Yale, 1919-1920 (folder 2 of 2), 215248 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    Includes an invitation to the Yale graduation ceremony and a letter sent from the Republican National Convention in Chicago.
  - Europe and Oxford, July 1920-June 23, 1921 (folder 1 of 2), 1920-1921; 215251 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    Includes a letter from Geneva, Switzerland describing HRL's experiences at the League of Nations, and a letter regarding his smoking and drinking habits.
  - Europe and Oxford, July 1920-June 23, 1921 (folder 2 of 2), 1920-1921; 215252 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    Includes letters sent from Germany, postcards of Oare Church and Lynmouth Bay, and an account of HRL's trip on the Orient Express.
  - Chicago, Baltimore and New York, 1921-1922, 215254 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    Includes correspondence regarding HRL's working on and being fired from The Chicago News, a detailed letter from HRL to his father regarding the selection of the name "TIME" for the new magazine, potential slogans, and its development and financing.
  - Letters Regarding TIME, 1925-1938 & 1947-1948, 215261 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    Includes a letter dealing with the purchase of Time Inc. stock from the Hadden estate, a clipping with a caricature of HRL at the Banff Conference, a letter dealing with prohibition of liquor advertisements, a letter to HRL's father from Corinne Thrasher with an attached memo regarding a speech HRL made at the Yale Barn affair on the degradation of civilization. Also includes a carbon copy of a letter to Winston Churchill and a letter from HRL to his mother apologizing for a TIME article on Amsterdam.
  - Unsorted Letters, 1923-1939 (folder 1 of 2), 215255 (Box 75, Folder 7)
    Includes letters mentioning a meeting with Conde Nast, wedding to Lila Luce, the birth of Henry Luce III and Peter Paul Luce, and a letter from Lila Luce to HRL's mother.
  - Unsorted Letters, 1923-1939 (folder 2 of 2), 215257 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    Includes a postcard of the Haleakala Crater in Maui, a letter sent to Kay and Reese Taylor, letters sent from HRL's first round the world trip in 1932, a letter from Lila Luce to HRL's mother with paper notes used by HRL to communicate with his wife and a nurse when he was undergoing a medical procedure, a letter discussing his appointment to have tea with Franklin D. Roosevelt, and an invitation to an exhibition and sale of items brought from England by Miss Florence T. Gay.
  - Unsorted Letters, 1940-1948 (folder 1 of 2), 215259 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Unsorted Letters, 1940-1948 (folder 2 of 2), 215260 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Transcriptions, 215496 (Box -, Folder -)
  - Transcription Project Correspondence, 1972-1973; 215497 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Index and Elm Excerpts, circa 1972-1973; 215498 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Index for Letters from HRL Covering Pages 218-583, circa 1972-1973; 215499 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Transcription Manuscript (4 of 7 folders), circa 1972-1973; 215500 (Box 76, Folder 6-9)
  - Transcription Manuscript (3 of 7 folders), circa 1972-1973; 215501 (Box 77, Folder 1-3)
  - Photostats and Negatives, 215502 (Box -, Folder -)
  - From the Beginning, 1898-1905; 215505 (Offsite-box RC12, Folder 10)
  - Letters, 1906-1907; 215506 (Offsite-box RC12, Folder 11)
  - Iltus Huk and Chefoo, 1908; 215507 (Offsite-box RC12, Folder 12)
  - Chefoo, 1909-1910; 215508 (Offsite-box RC12, Folder 13)
  - Chefoo (2 folders), 1911-1912; 215509 (Offsite-box RC13, Folder 1-2)
  - Trip to Suez, England, Europe, USA to Hotchkiss, 1912-1913; 215510 (Offsite-box RC13, Folder 3)
  - Hotchkiss (4 folders), 1913-1916; 215511 (Offsite-box RC13, Folder 4-7)
  - Hotchkiss and Yale Poems, 1913-1920; 215512 (Offsite-box RC13, Folder 8)
  - Hotchkiss and Yale Orations, Speeches, etc., 1913-1920; 215517 (Offsite-box RC13, Folder 9)
  - Summer of 1916 at Springfield before Yale, 215513 (Offsite-box RC13, Folder 10)
  - Yale, 1916-1917; 215514 (Offsite-box RC13, Folder 11)
  - Summer of 1917, 215515 (Offsite-box RC13, Folder 12)
  - Yale (2 folders), 1917-1920; 215516 (Offsite-box RC14, Folder 1-2)
  - Europe and Oxford, 1920-1921; 215518 (Offsite-box RC14, Folder 3)
  - Chicago, Baltimore and New York, 1921-1922; 215519 (Offsite-box RC14, Folder 4)
  - Personal Unsorted, 1923-1939; 215520 (Offsite-box RC14, Folder 5)
  - Personal Unsorted, 1940-1948; 215521 (Offsite-box RC14, Folder 6)
  - Personal Regarding TIME, 1925-1938, 1947-1948; 215522 (Offsite-box RC14, Folder 6)
  - From the Beginning (2 folders), 1898-1905; 215523 (Offsite-box RC14, Folder 7)
  - Letters (2 folders), 1906-1907; 215524 (Offsite-box RC14, Folder 8-9)
  - Iltus Huk and Chefoo (2 folders), 1908; 215525 (Offsite-box RC14, Folder 10-11)
  - Chefoo (4 folders), 1909-1910; 215526 (Offsite-box RC14, Folder 12-13)
  - Chefoo (4 folders), 1911-1912; 215527 (Offsite-box RC15, Folder 1-4)
  - Trip to Suez, England, Europe, USA (2 folders), 1912-1913; 215528 (Offsite-box RC15, Folder 5-6)
  - Hotchkiss (6 folders), 1913-1916; 215532 (Offsite-box RC15, Folder 7-12)
  - Hotchkiss, 1916; 215533 (Offsite-box RC16, Folder 1)
  - Hotchkiss and Yale Poems (2 folders), circa 1905, 1913-1920; 215534 (Offsite-box RC16, Folder 2)
  - Hotchkiss and Yale Orations, Speeches, etc. (3 folders), 1913-1920; 215535 (Offsite-box RC16, Folder 2-3)
  - Hotchkiss and Yale Test and Examination Papers, 1913-1920; 215536 (Offsite-box RC16, Folder 4)
  - Summer of 1916 at Springfield before Yale (2 folders), 215537 (Offsite-box RC16, Folder 5)
  - Yale (2 folders), 1916-1917; 215538 (Offsite-box RC16, Folder 6-7)
  - Summer of 1917 (2 folders), 215539 (Offsite-box RC16, Folder 8-9)
  - Yale (2 folders), 1917-1918; 215540 (Offsite-box RC16, Folder 10)
  - Wartime Letters and Return to Yale (2 folders), 1918; 215541 (Offsite-box RC17, Folder 1-2)
  - Yale Daily News Special File, 1918; 215542 (Offsite-box RC17, Folder 3)
  - Yale (2 folders), 1919-1920; 215543 (Offsite-box RC17, Folder 4)
  - Europe and Oxford (2 folders), 1920-1921; 215544 (Offsite-box RC17, Folder 5-6)
  - Chicago, Baltimore, and New York, 1921-1922; 215545 (Offsite-box RC17, Folder 7)
  - Personal Unsorted (3 folders), 1923-1939; 215546 (Offsite-box RC17, Folder 8-10)
  - Personal Unsorted, 1940-1948; 215547 (Offsite-box RC17, Folder 11)
  - Personal Unsorted (2 folders), 1940-1948; 215550 (Offsite-box RC18, Folder 1)
  - Personal Regarding TIME Magazine (2 folders), 1925-1938, 1947-1948; 215551 (Offsite-box RC18, Folder 2-3)
- Series V. Subject Name Files, 1894-1995 (bulk 1933-1967); 205880; 30.1 Linear feet
  Subseries V.A. Name Files A
  Subseries V.B. Name Files B
  Many names are found in both subseries.
  Series consists of files with correspondence, memoranda, and printed materials to and from the named individual, with a third party/parties about the named individual or background and research materials on the named individual.
  - Subseries V.A. Name Files A, 1894-1995 (bulk 1933-1967); 205881
    The subseries is arranged in alphabetical order by subject's name.
    The majority of the documents in the subseries appear to be mainly related to Time Inc., its publications, and the subject of publishing in general. In some cases the subjects of the files are submitting an article, are being solicited to submit a manuscript or are themselves the subjects of an article being written by someone else.
    Materials related to Time Inc. publications consist of correspondence dealing with complaints from individuals on behalf of themselves or the organizations they work for or represent; compliments and encouragements after reading an article; letters of gratitude for being mentioned in a publication, appearing on the cover, or for receiving favorable coverage; article suggestions; requests for reprints and images that have appeared in the publications; proposals for new magazines and other publications; letters of gratitude for receiving Time Inc. publications, speech reprints or other gifts sent by Henry R. Luce (hereafter HRL); and correspondence giving the sender's general opinion, suggestion and advice.
    There are also carbon copies of responses from HRL and other Time Inc. staff; internal memoranda dealing with the investigation of complaints received, suggestions and advice on how HRL should respond, and drafts of responses to the individual making the complaint; discussion memoranda on how the subject individual will be covered in an upcoming story; correspondence and memoranda discussing payments for articles; and internal memos to HRL from Time Inc. staff giving him summaries of conversations they had with various individuals.
    There is also correspondence to HRL where the subject individuals are giving their general opinion on a variety of topics including economics, politics, foreign affairs, as well as apprising HRL of interesting things they have discovered and updating him of the news from where they are; asking for his endorsements for projects they are working on or his support or sponsorship of an initiative or issue they are working on; requests for jobs at Time Inc. and letters of recommendations; and letters forwarding various publications, clippings, essays, and article drafts for HRL's information and opinion.
    In addition there are HRL's letters of congratulations to other publications marking their anniversaries; memoranda dealing with dinner arrangements with biographical sketches of individuals to be present; requests for meetings and appointments, and arrangements to be made; a large number of letters of gratitude and other responses to invitations to attend the 40th anniversary of TIME in 1963; invitations to speak; letters of condolences following HRL's death with acknowledgements; and clippings on subjects added to their files after HRL's death.
    There are a number of files in the subseries on HRL's family members, including his father, mother, sisters, and youngest son with photographs, correspondence, printed materials, and background information. There is also a file on HRL himself with excerpts from family correspondence. (See also series IV.)
    - A - General, 1935-1964; 215552 (Box 77, Folder 4)
      Includes a carbon copy of an article regarding Whittaker Chambers "A Witness to Unpopular Truth: It Pleases God to Have in Readiness a Man" by Adolph J. Ackerman and a signed carbon copy of a letter from Carl W. Ackerman to Westbrook Pegler. Correspondents include Mehemed Fehmy Agha, Margaret Cobb Ailshie, and Mustafa Amin.
    - Abs, Herman J., 1957-1963; 215553 (Box 77, Folder 5)
      Includesa letter from Abs requesting HRL to publish a letter addressed to President Eisenhower, excerpts from Abs's speech "Tasks and Problems of Monetary and Financial Policy," and a memo titled "Progress Report on the Abs Magna Carta."
    - Adams, Robert McCormick, 1936-1944; 215554 (Box 77, Folder 5)
      Includes correspondence discussing the 1944 presidential election.
    - Adler, Mortimer, 1950-1963; 215555 (Box 77, Folder 5)
      Includes a memo discussing Adler's essay "The Capitalist Revolution."
    - Alba, Duke of, 1952; 215556 (Box 77, Folder 5)
      Contains correspondence dealing with the Duke's reaction to LIFE's Picture History of Western Man.
    - Aldrich, Winthrop, 1935-1974; 215558 (Box 77, Folder 5)
      Includes a letter inviting HRL to join the New York Chamber of Commerce.
    - Algase, Gertrude, 1946; 215559 (Box 77, Folder 6)
      Includes an "Outline of Proposed Book and Magazine Series to be Completed October 1946 by Major General J. Russell Deane, Chief of U.S. Military Mission to Russia - 1943 to 1945."
    - Allen, Raymond B., 1948-1959; 215560 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Alsop, Joseph and Stewart, 1940-1958; 215561 (Box 77, Folder 6)
      Includes correspondence dealing with the publication American White Paper. Also includes an untitled article draft regarding politics following the envisioned victory of Thomas Dewey in the 1948 presidential elections.
    - Anderson, Robert B., 1957-1963; 215562 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Andrade, C. (Dick), 1942-1960; 215563 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Andrews, Donald Hatch, 1962-1967; 215564 (Box 78, Folder 1)
      Includes a project proposal and outline for the manuscript New Ideas for the War of Ideas by Edward W. Russell.
    - Annenberg, Walter H., 1947-1959; 215565 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Arneta, Salvador, 1951; 215566 (Box 78, Folder 2)
      Includes a memo-summary regarding the speech on "Philippine-American Relations."
    - Arends, L.C., 1948; 215567 (Box 78, Folder 2)
      Includes a letter from Congressman Arends dealing with LIFE coverage of Republican presidential candidates in the 1948 election.
    - Arens, Egmont, 1929-1936; 215568 (Box 78, Folder 2)
      Includes a typescript copy of a 1929 letter from Arens to Ogden Reid regarding a modern pictorial magazine, the proposal "A Modern Rotogravure Section - Why & How," and an offer from Egmont to help HRL with his magazine.
    - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1937-1973; 215569 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Astor, Nancy (Lady), 1940-1943; 215570 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Auchincloss, Hugh D., 1963-1967; 215571 (Box 78, Folder 2)
      Includes a letter from Auchincloss to Robert Elson giving an account of a trip with HRL through the Balkans in 1920.
    - Austin, Warren, 1950-1951; 215572 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - An-Ay - General, 1935-1972; 215573 (Box 78, Folder 3)
      Includes the pamphlet "Salient Facts About China" by Julean Arnold and a memorandum dealing with Bromwell Ault's proposals for helping Britain. Correspondents include Roy Chapman Andrews, Bert Andrews, Marian Anderson, Elizabeth Arden, Fred Astaire, Brooks Atkinson, and Thurman Arnold.
    - B - General (folder 1 of 2), 1935-1973; 215575 (Box 78, Folder 4)
      Includes a memo from O.P. Swift to HRL about a potential meeting with Senator Josiah W. Bailey. Correspondents include Raymond E. Baldwin, Mary Bancroft, Philip Barry, George W. Beadle, Ingmar Bergman, Milton Berle, and S. N. Behman.
    - B - General (folder 2 of 2), 1935-1965; 215576 (Box 78, Folder 5)
      Correspondents include Rudolf Bing and Hugo L. Black.
    - Baillie, Hugh, 1935-1951; 215577 (Box 78, Folder 6)
      Includes a carbon copy of a letter from Baillie to Archibald MacLeish regarding "freedom of the news."
    - Baker, Frederick E., 1946-1957; 215579 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Baldridge, Letitia (Mrs. R. Hollinsteiner), 1953-1964; 215582 (Box 78, Folder 6)
      Baldridge worked as Clare Boothe Luce's social secretary.
    - Ball, Joseph, 1944; 215583 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Barnes, Roswell P., 1965; 215584 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Barton, Bruce, 1937-1956; 215585 (Box 78, Folder 6)
      Includes a letter from Wesley Front of the U.S. Legation of Asuncion, Paraguay to Barton asking him to influence HRL to write more positive news regarding the Allies in TIME, and a carbon copy of a letter from Barton's son sent from the Pacific Front.
    - Baruch, Bernard M., 1937-1963; 215590 (Box 79, Folder 1)
      Includes Baruch's statement before the Military Affairs Committee of the Senate, an off-the-record memorandum from McDonald to Paine and the Board of Editors regarding a meeting with Baruch, and a letter to HRL from Francis T. Spaulding regarding LIFE gift subscriptions made by Baruch.
    - Barzini, Luigi, 1939-1964; 215591 (Box 79, Folder 1)
      Includes notes by an unnamed Italian ambassador on the Italian situation.
    - Barzun, Jacques, 1950-1963; 215592 (Box 79, Folder 1)
      Includes materials dealing with the critique of TIME in the book The House of Intellect.
    - Bates, Sanford, 1953; 215593 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Beard, Charles A., 1944-1971; 215594 (Box 79, Folder 1)
      Includes the pamphlet "The Truth About Pearl Harbor" by John T. Flynn, an essay received by Beard and forwarded to HRL, and correspondence from Alfred Vagts to Henry Luce III and Lillian Owens.
    - Beitz, Berthold, 1956-1963; 215595 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Benes, Dr., 1943; 215596 (Box 79, Folder 2)
      Contains correspondence between HRL and Vladimir Hurban mentioning Benes.
    - Benson, Ezra.T., 1953-1963; 215597 (Box 79, Folder 2)
      Includes correspondence dealing with the issue of agriculture in the United States.
    - Benton, William B. (folder 1 of 2), 1936-1960; 228208 (Box 183, Folder 3)
      Includes a carbon copy memorandum with story suggestions from the field of the biological sicences by Professor Joseph J. Schwab, Benton's article "The Economics of a Free Society: A Declaration of American Business Policy" reprinted from FORTUNE in pamphlet form, and a memorandum regarding the Freedom of Information Conference, and a reprint of "William Benton Reports on the Voice of the Kremlin."
    - Benton, William B. (folder 2 of 2), 1960-1973; 228209 (Box 183, Folder 4)
      Includes a copy of the "Proposal for a Commission on the Mass Media," an original signed letter from Carl Solberg, and a letter from Benton written following HRL's death with background materials labeled "Time Magazine and Senator Joseph R. McCarthy."
    - Berdan, John, 1935-1962; 215598 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Berlin, Isaiah, 1945-1950; 215599 (Box 79, Folder 2)
      Contains mostly photocopies.
    - Bernays, Edward, 1936-1965, 1995; 215600 (Box 79, Folder 3)
      Includes correspondence dealing with HRL's and Time Inc.'s public relations. Also includes a typescript copy of a letter from C. J. Friedrich to Bernays regarding fighting the fifth column in the Americas, a memo regarding problems facing the country and their solutions, and the pamphlet "A Challenge to Business."
    - Bernstein, Henri, 1941; 215601 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Beschloss, Michael R., 1978-1981; 215602 (Box 79, Folder 4)
      Contains correspondence regarding research in the Luce Archive.
    - Bessie, Simon Michael, 1963-1965; 215603 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Biddle, Anthony J., 1940-1952; 215604 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Bijur, George, 1938-1939; 215610 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Billinkopf, Jacob, 1937-1942; 215611 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Billingsley, Allen, 1938-1954; 215613 (Box 79, Folder 4)
      Includes a letter from C.C. Carr to Billingsley regarding FORTUNE.
    - Bimson, Walter, 1957-1965; 215614 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Birdwell, Russell, 1941-1963; 215616 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Birla, Ghashyam Das, 1962; 215617 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Black, Eugene R., 1954-1965; 215618 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Blaine, James G., 1939-1953; 215619 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Blake, Eugene Carson, 1960-1968; 215620 (Box 79, Folder 6)
      Includes a copy of a letter written by HRL but not mailed with the memorandum "Poverty: A Memo for Cursory Research."
    - Bliven, Bruce, 1940-1957; 215621 (Box 79, Folder 6)
      Includes a preliminary draft of an untitled article? by Bliven.
    - Boomer, Lucius, 1936-1945; 215623 (Box 79, Folder 6)
      Includes Boomer's address "Executive Housekeepers and Employee Problems" from the Annual Congress of the National Executive Housekeepers Association, Inc.
    - Bowles, Chester, 1937-1963; 215624 (Box 80, Folder 1)
      Includes a draft of an article for LIFE by Bowles.
    - Bowron, Mayor Fletcher, 1946-1947; 215625 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Br-By - General, 1937-1970; 215626 (Box 80, Folder 2)
      Includes the pamphlet "A Letter of Desperation" from World Neighbors, Inc. Correspondents include Edward W. Brooke, Edmund G. Brown, Harry F. Byrd, and August A. Busch, Jr.
    - Brainard, Morgan B., 1939; 215627 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Breasted, Charles, 1936-1937; 215628 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Bricker, John, 1943-1963; 215629 (Box 80, Folder 3)
      Includes a speech made by Governor Bricker at the Annual State Lincoln Day Dinner.
    - Bridges, Styles, 1950-1956; 215630 (Box 80, Folder 4)
      Includes a speech by Bridges made on the floor of the United States Senate.
    - Brinkley, Alan, 1990-1991; 215631 (Box 80, Folder 3)
      Includes a copy of a contract for a Henry R. Luce biography.
    - Bromfield, Louis, 1942-1947; 215632 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Brosio, Manlio, 1955-1956; 215633 (Box 80, Folder 4)
      Includes Vol. 1, No. 2 of America-Italy Newsletter.
    - Brown, Cecil, 1942-1959; 215634 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Brown, Lewis H., 1942-1950; 215635 (Box 80, Folder 4)
      Includes the memorandum "The Dangerous Spence Bill."
    - Brownnell, Herbert, 1944-1963; 215636 (Box 80, Folder 4)
      Includes a carbon copy letter discussing polling numbers in the 1944 presidential elections.
    - Bruckberger, Father R. L., 1951-1960; 215637 (Box 80, Folder 4)
      Includes memoranda dealing with Bruckberger's writing projects.
    - Bryan, Hamilton V., 1941-1942; 215638 (Box 80, Folder 4)
      Contains correspondence and memoranda regarding the ship "Sea Otter."
    - Buchanan, Jr. Wiley T., 1958-1962; 215639 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Buck, Pearl, 1941-1973; 215640 (Box 80, Folder 5)
      Includes a copy of the "Private Memorandum on Pearl Buck's Article on China" and a working draft of the "Essay on Love" by Buck.
    - Buckley, Jr. William F., 1964-1966; 215641 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Bullitt, William, 1937-1972; 215642 (Box 80, Folder 6)
      Includes a detailed report on Bullitt, a "Bullitt Dossier" and critical observations on an article by Bullitt.